Wild Squirrel Recruitment

Rachel Ayeh-Datey

Rachel is a writer, editor, strategist and researcher. She is currently the Editor-in-Chief of Chapter Z, an inclusive online publication aimed at Gen Z audiences. She has 5 years of experience in advertising in research and strategy. Uncovering lesser-known narratives through storytelling is one of her biggest passions. This can be seen through her freelance writing commissions.

Education

Sep 2013 – July 2016 University of Southampton

Achieved a 2:1 History BA

Sep 2011 – June 2013 Woodhouse Sixth Form College

A-Levels achieved: A in English Literature, A in History and B in Psychology.

Sep 2006 – July 2011 Copland Community School

GCSE's: 12 A*-C GCSE grades.

Employment

January 2021-Present

Chapter Z, Editor-in-Chief

- <u>Chapter Z</u> is an online publication focused on creating content for Gen Z audiences; specifically those from marginalised backgrounds. The content topics that the magazine focuses on are Thought & Opinion, Community, Fashion & Beauty, Music, Tech, Art & Culture, Self Care and Video.
- Managing a team of 5 editors and a freelance graphic designer.
- Commissioning insightful and introspective stories from young contributors.
- Regular editing of written submissions
- Posting daily content on Chapter Z's website using WordPress.
- Creating social media graphics to promote the articles
- Building knowledge of Html ad tags which live on Chapter Z's website & articles
- Liaising with brands and influencers for content partnerships

September 2020-Present

Freelance Writer

- Writing and editing articles and pieces of prose which focus on Black British History, social justice and queer identities
- Published in Meetings of Mind, AZ Mag, twice in Sistem Magazine

January 2020-December 2020

BBH, Senior Data

Strategist

Main responsibilities:

 Management, execution and delivery of regular and ad hoc/campaign reporting, including competitor benchmarking and landscape analysis.

Rachel Ayeh-Datey

- Management of junior members of the team
- Working with different departments (i.e. Strategy, Editorial, Client Services, Creative) to create social insights into audiences, brands or industry categories, to drive our creative strategies and executions
- Social insights lead for Tesco. Establishing and communicating findings & insights and proposing recommendations to departmental client leads & client contacts
- Wrote one of BBH's most successful Labs <u>article</u> about inclusivity for International Women's Day
- Working with Senior leadership teams to implement diversity & inclusion practices

October 2018- December 2019

We Are Social, Research & Insights

Analyst

Main responsibilities: Management, execution and delivery of regular and ad hoc/campaign reporting, including competitor benchmarking and landscape analysis

- Setting up of measurement and effectiveness frameworks, to measure the success of our creative campaign against business and marketing objectives
- Establishing and communicating findings & insights and proposing recommendations to departmental client leads & client contacts
- Worked on an ethnography project about Gen Z's. For the project, I wrote the discussion guide and interviewed 13 18-24 year old's from across the UK. We found out how they used social media and interacted with brands. This was turned into a report which can be found here. This report was premiered at AdWeek in 2019.
- Completed an Introduction to Moderating training held by the Market Research Society
- Worked on cultural research pieces
- Worked with senior leadership teams to implement diversity & inclusion practices
- Clients: Disney, YouTube, Compare the Market, Vodafone, Adidas

December 2017 – October 2018

VCCP Kin, Junior Data Planner

- Main Responsibilities: Worked to incorporate data-led consumer insight across creative strategy, channel optimisation, and media planning.
- Research into cultural insights which impact consumer behaviour
- Worked with senior leadership teams to implement diversity & inclusion practices
- Clients: Canon, easyJet, Triumph, Nationwide, Cadbury's, Vita Coco, Triumph, O2

December 2016 – December 2017 Beamly, Social Media Analyst

 Main Responsibilities: Develop deep-dive reports using social listening tools that provide a review of a brand's digital performance compared to its industry competitors.

Rachel Ayeh-Datey

- Identify and analyse impactful hair, luxury and beauty trends across social media which are delivered in a monthly report format.
- Examples of brands I've completed work for: Wella, Shockwaves, Gucci and Rimmel, Adidas, Wilko.
- Analysis of social listening data to give brand insights to clients.
- Influencer Identification
- **Achievements:** I was the sole social media analyst working on one of the most expensive client briefs for major sports brand Adidas.

Skills

IT – Proficient in Microsoft Office, WordPress, Canva. Regular user of social media platforms including Twitter, LinkedIn, Tumblr, TikTok, Instagram and Facebook Research/Social Listening Tools – Netbase, Crimson Hexagon, Talkwalker, BrandWatch, Synthesio, Google Analytics, Demographics Pro, GWI, YouGov

Achievements and Interests

Currently volunteering on a Haringey Vanguard's oral history project collecting the stories of older BAME LGBTQ+ people. Regularly volunteering at London Metropolitan Archives